# Curriculum Vitae

# **Paul Richard Sewart**

Home location Selby M: 07718 895 352 paul\_sewart@hotmail.com

# **Summary**

A highly motivated Scheme Project Manager and Senior Project Engineer, working in signalling installation CRE roles and as CEM. Experienced in delivering railway signalling projects, managing client expectations and providing leadership and organisational skills for multidisciplinary teams. Possessing strong collaboration skills and a willingness to engage with site staff and office based personnel to progress projects to a successful conclusion. Uses effective communication skills and is IT literate. Full driving licence, own car.

### Education

BSc (Hons) 2:1 in Product Design, Thames Valley University 1995 Association of Project management Qualified Personal track Safety (AC/DC) Basic Signalling Training Testing MOD 5 trained. First Aid at Work

# Skill summary

#### Leadership

- Experience in managing people in industry and in the voluntary sector.
- APM trained and qualified to manage people and projects.
- Leads by example and is willing to set the standard for others to follow.
- Understands client concerns and is able to manage client aspirations.
- Is able to motivate and inspire others by fostering relationships and demonstrating integrity.
- 23 years' service as an Adult volunteer in the Royal Air Force Air Cadets.

# **Engineering**

- Working in accordance with engineering standards to deliver rail signalling projects to contract technical requirements, programmes and budgets.
- Leading and coordinating site based teams to build and install to design.
- Managing interfaces between disciplines and coordinating site works.
- Liaising with management from both the project team and the client organisation to manage expectations and resolve issues.
- Experience of Level Crossing and Re-signalling Schemes.

# **Work History**

2018-Date	Network Rail (Contractor)	Scheme Project Manager
2013-2018	Babcock International	Senior Project Engineer (Signalling)
2077-2013	Signalling Solutions	Scheme Project Manager
2006-2007	Balfour Beatty.	Scheme Project Manager
2004-2006	Balfour Beatty	Level Crossing Ground plan Designer/Checker
2002-2004	Parsons Brinckerhoff	Level Crossing Ground plan Designer/Checker
2000-2002	Corus Rail Consultancy	Level Crossing Ground plan Designer
1998-2000	Westinghouse	Assistant Signalling & Level Crossing Ground plan Designer.